

#### **Address**

301,Swastik Divine, Bh . Shaswat homes,

science city road ,sola ,Ahmedabad Ahmedabad-380059

#### Contact

+91 8128076969 harshbharad7@gmail.com

**Date of Birth** 

04.11.1996

# **PROFILE**

I have an experience of **1YEAR & 2 MONTH** of ship design and electrical design experience looking to secure a design engineer trainee position as well as modeler position with TECHSHIP design & engineering solutions Where we handle full of projects with creating BOM, cable schedule, design modification. I have **2 YEARS** solar field experience for surveying of sites and installation of ROOFTOP SYSTEM. Recently i am working as a PRODUCTION & TESTING ENGINEER at HKRP INNOVATIONS(HARIKRUPA AUTOMATION) Which is IOT based SMART METER SCADA PANELS, SMART METERING CONSOLE FOR REAL TIME MONITORING FOR DISCOMS from last 1 Year, 4 Month.

# **EXPERIENCE**

August 2018 - June 2019

#### GREEN EARTH SOLAR, BOTAD.

Electrical engineer (Service & Maintainance engineer)

- In this organization i worked for solar rooftop surveying,
- document collection & verification,
- installation, supervision on site.

July 2019 - October 2020

#### TECHSHIP Design & Engineering solution Pvt.Ltd.

Graduate engineer trainee

Responsibilities

- Design & install blast water treatment system and scrubber system in ship's existing system
- ship electrical design
- ship electrical load analysis and guide to clients for respective modification in breaker setting, cable size etc.
- Prepating BOM & system equipment load calculation

October 2020 - November 2021

#### **GREEN EARTH SOLAR PVT.LTD**

Electrical engineer (surveying and installation)

- In this organization i worked for solar rooftop surveying, Marketing,
- SURVEYING & INSTALLATION HANDLING on site.
- DOCUMENTATION

# HARSH BHARAD

PRODUCTION & TESTING ENGINEER (ELECTRICAL ENGINEER)

# **EDUCATION**

June 2014 - June 2018

#### Darshan inst. of Engineering & Technology, Rajkot.

Bachlor of Electrical Engineering

May 2012 - May 2014

#### Adarsh Vidhyalaya, Botad.

High school in science

May 2011 - April 2012

#### M.D.Shah vidhyalaya, Botad.

Secondary school education

### **PERSONALITY**

Communicative

Punctuality

Creativity

Organized

Hard working (Goal oriented)

Quick learner

Honest

Faithfull for my nation.

self motivated

Intransigent in work

#### **SKILLS**

Good communication - written and oral skills

Excellent conceptual and analytical skills

Effective interpersonal skills

Leadership skills

Project management skills

Project planning

**Documentation list** 

Self-Motivated

Discipline

February 2022 - present

#### HKRP innovations (Harikrupa Automation)

PRODUCTION & TESTING ENGINEER

- Production of IOT DCU based solar systems for monitoring.
- Right now i worked as a production IN charge for the projects like UGVCL,PGVCL,DGVCL,MGVCL,GSECL,PMKUSUM KERALA,SKY,ONGC PROJECTS.
- As well as we will doing (VFD) drive testing, panel testing etc.
- parallelly i worked as a project engineer for feeder segregation project.

# SOFTWARE SKILLS

•••••
•••••
•••••
•••••
•••••
•••••
•••••
•••••
•••••

# FINAL YEAR PROJECT DETAILS

Project :Power factor correction by using power electronic device and capacitor banks.

• A high power factor is generally desirable in a power delivery system to reduce losses and improve voltage regulation at the load. Compensating elements near an electrical load will reduce the apparent power demand on the supply system. Power factor correction may be applied by an electric power transmission utility to improve the stability and efficiency of the network. Individual electrical customers who are charged by their utility for low power factor may install correction equipment to increase their power factor so as to reduce costs.

# LANGUAGES

English	•••••
Hindi	•••••
Gujarati	000000

# TECHINICAL EVENTS AND WORKSHOPS

- 3 days Solar Rooftop System Program by MSME.
- 4 days Variable Frequency Drive training seminar By siemens at PDPU, Gandhinagar.
- 3 days Certified by Indian Robotics lab seminar
- 4 days certified training on Solar PV system Analysis & Simulation.

# INDUSTRIAL VISIT

- Electrical locoshade at Vadodara.
- Nuclear Power plant at Kakrapar, Guajrat.
- Thermal Power plant, Sikka, Jamnagar.
- Hydro power plant(sardar sarovar dam), Kevadiya.

### **HOBBIES**









Chess, Cricket

 $Listening\,music$ 

cooking routine food

# REFERENCES

JAYDIP BHADIYADARA PRODUCTION ER,HEAD CONTACT:989862995